# Cassandra Duchesneau

366 Waverley Street, Unit 2 • Ottawa, ON, K2P 0W5 • Phone: (613) 277-7013 • E-mail: cassie.duchesneau@gmail.com

### **Profile**

My name is Cassandra Duchesneau and I am a front-end developer at Cinnamon Toast New Media. I am a graduate of Algonquin College and Concordia University. At Algonquin I did a graduate certificate program for Interactive Multimedia. At Concordia I completed a Bachelor of Arts undergraduate degree for Communications Studies with a specialization in Intermedia.

I have 5+ years of experience as a front-end developer. I am bilingual, have plenty of customer service experience and am excellent at time management. I am a team player and am looking for the opportunity to succeed/grow in a working environment while expressing my creativity through multiple different projects.

## **Relevant Experience**

### **Front-End Developer**

Cinnamon Toast New Media Inc.

March 2015 - Ongoing

Cinnamon Toast New Media Inc. is a full service agency that specializes in integrated design solutions that build brand identities and update current visual marketing presences for companies and individuals through print, digital and nontraditional media.

As a front-end developer, I collaborate with our team of designers, developers and content strategists to deliver stunning websites to our clients. I also act as a mentor to our junior developers to make sure that they are following best practices and staying up to date with the latest development trends.

#### **Professor**

School of Media and Design - Algonquin College

September 2014 - April 2015

As a professor at Algonquin, I taught students in both the 2-year Interactive Media Designer diploma program and the 1-year Interactive Multimedia Management graduate certificate program.

It was my job to introduce students to the basics of Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash.

The courses I taught included: Graphic Technologies Design and Authoring Multimedia and Design II

### **Program Assistant**

Interactive Multimedia - Algonquin College

September 2014 - April 2015

As a program assistant for the Interactive Multimedia post-graduate program, I assisted students with HTML, CSS, Photoshop, Illustrator, etc. Some of my duties included in-class help as well as private tutoring sessions should they be needed.

### **Education**

## **Algonquin College**

Interactive Multimedia

Fall 2013 - Spring 2014

I am an honors graduate of Algonquin College where I did a graduate certificate program in Interactive Multimedia. This program has provided me with experience in project planning, management, design, development and prototyping various multimedia projects from conception to completion. Some of the topics in this program included graphic layout, web design, web development, interface architecture, motion graphics, video composition, and Flash animation.

### **Concordia University**

**Communication Studies** 

Fall 2008 - Spring 2012

I am a graduate of Concordia University. I graduated from Concordia with a B.A. in Communications Studies, where I specialized within the Intermedia stream of the communications department. As a communications student at Concordia, I had the privilege of developing both a theoretical and practical understanding of the media. By studying within the Intermedia stream, I established many skills in multiple media outlets such as film, video, sound, and computer software.

# **Skills Highlights**

Markup Languages: HTML5, SASS, JQuery, PHP, Liquid

CMS: Wordpress, Shopify Framework: Bootstrap

Server Technologies: MAMP, WAMP

Version Management: Git, Github, Bitbucket

OS: Mac, Windows
Other: Gulp, npm

#### **Awards**

#### **Dean's Honours List**

Algonquin College - Faculty of Arts, Media and Design

### Portfolio Website

dinosysrobots.ca